Prey. Slay. Display.
House of Wax is a horror, thriller, mystery film directed by Jaume Collet-Serra.
A group of unwitting teens are stranded near a strange wax museum and soon
must fight to survive and keep from becoming the next exhibit.
Carly Jones, played by Elisha Cuthbert.
Nick Jones, played by Chad Michael Murray.
Bo Sinclair / Vincent Sinclair, played by Brian Van Holt.
Paige Edwards, played by Paris Hilton.
Wade Felton, played by Jared Padalecki.
Blake Johnson, played by Robert Ri'chard.
House of Wax is a 2005 slasher film directed by Jaume Collet-Serra, in his feature directorial debut, and starring Elisha Cuthbert,
Chad Michael Murray, Brian Van Holt in a dual role, Paris Hilton, Jared Padalecki, Jon Abrahams, and Robert Ri'chard.
It is a remake of the 1953 film of the same name, itself a remake of the 1933 film
Mystery of the Wax Museum, based on the story "The Wax Works" by Charles S.
The screenplay, written by Chad Hayes and Carey W.
Hayes, follows a group of teenagers who become stranded in a
seemingly abandoned town containing an elaborate wax museum.
The soundtrack features music by bands including Deftones, My
Chemical Romance, Joy Division, and Interpol.
House of Wax premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival and was released in
United States theaters on May 6, 2005, by Warner Bros.
It grossed $70.1 million worldwide and received generally negative reviews from critics, who criticized its
lack of originality, screenplay, and characters, but praised the performances and atmosphere.
It has gained a cult following in the years since its release.
The film explores themes of louisiana, gore, traffic jam, remake, murder.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.